

Mohammad Ali Danish

Date of birth: 29/12/1996 | **Nationality:** Afghan | **Gender:** Male |

Phone number: (+93) 0764082247 (Mobile) | Email address:

mohammadalidanish2017@gmail.com

Address: Shahid Mazari, Street, Kabul, Afghanistan, 13 Area, Shahid Mazari, Street, Kabul, Afghanistan, 1016, Kabul, Afghanistan (Home)

ABOUT ME

I am a person with an open forehead and good manners, always striving to be honest, sincere, and enjoyable in both my educational and professional pursuits. Honesty is a priority for me. Additionally, I am a creative person and always pay attention to detail. As an enthusiastic person, I pass through the windows of life and strive to achieve my goals, while finding adherence to order and valuing time in all tasks enjoyable. I also greatly enjoy group work. Respectful behavior towards all people is one of my strongest personal traits. I love all members of the community, and I am entirely sociable, and participating in voluntary activities has been one of my goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

10/02/2020 - 15/04/2023 Kabul, Afghanistan

FULL STACK DEVELOPER ABARBIT TECHNOLOGY SERVICES COMPANY

- •Developed a fully responsive website for Dunya University of Afghanistan, facilitating online enrollment and advertising for students.
- Led the design, construction and implementation of the biometric system at Kabul Polytechnic University of Afghanistan. Contributed 40% of the overall effort, aligning the system with dormitory standards and enhancing student's facilitation.
- We built an interactive and reactive website called "Kankor of Afghanistan" for the Pupils participating in the Kankor examination.
- This platform, utilize by 70% of learners nationwide, allows students to select their majors at all universities.
- Improved the completion of ongoing projects by 60% within the company.
- Successfully orchestrated the migration of an e-commerce program from legacy PHP to React.js, and Node.js, building the entire stack from scratch; resulting in a 40% reduction in page load time and a 25% increase in conversation rate.
- Achieved and implemented a highly efficient ticketing system, reducing customer's response time by 50% and improving overall customer's satisfaction ratings by 30%.
- Ensured a ticketing platform to streamline communication between the company and its customers.
- Resolved multiple technical SEO issues, resulting in a 70% boost in search engine ranking and organic traffic

2018 - 2019 Kabul, Afghanistan

WEB DEVELOPER COLLEAGUE SMART FARIQI COMPANY

- ●Achieved an online system to facilitate communication between the teachers and students during Covid-19. And it was useful 50% and they were satisfied with this system.
- •Assistance in 55% of the different web applications projects with React.js + Node.js and from scratch with senior developer for customers.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

19/02/2017 - 09/04/2021 Kabul, Afghanistan

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER ENGINEERING AND INFORMATIC Kabul Polytechnic University

Address Karta-e-Mamorin KABUL/5TH DISTRICT, 1010, Kabul, Afghanistan, 1016, Kabul, Afghanistan

Website https://kpu.edu.af

21/03/2003 - 22/12/2015 Ghazni, Afghanistan

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA Sarab High School

Address Ghazni Province, 1003, Ghazni, Afghanistan, 1003, Ghazni, Afghanistan

Kabul, Afghanistan

DATABASE ANALYSIS & DESIGN AND MYSQL DATABASE COURSE Synapse Technologies

Address Kabul, Poli- Surkh, 1001, Kabul, Afghanistan, 1001, Kabul, Afghanistan

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **PERSIAN**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	B2	B2	B2	В2	В2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Web Design (HTML, CSS) | Programming (JavaScript) | Git, GitHub | DBMS (Database Analysis and Design, MySQL, SQLServer, PLSQL Oracle MongoDB) | Operating System (Windows, Linux) | Graphic Design (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign) | Office Package (Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

RECOMMENDATIONS

Faiz Mohammad Fagiry Instructor at Kabul Polytechnic University

I was Mr. Mohammad Ali Danish's lecturer in the Computer Engineering Department, Faculty of Computer Science at Kabul Polytechnic University. Due to his outstanding performance at the University, I am delighted to assist him in this process by writing this letter and I wholeheartedly would like to recommend him for this scholarship program.

Email Faiz.faqiry@kpu.edu.af | Phone (+93) 790721633

Mohammad Ali Hussainy Instructor at Kabul Polytechnic University

It is my pleasure to recommend Mr. Mohammad Ali Danish for the scholarship program. I have known Mohammad Ali for 3 years and was delighted to serve as his instructor and DEAN of Computer Science Faculty at Kabul Polytechnic University. I strongly believe that he is a perfect candidate for this scholarship.

Email Alihussainy78@gmail.com | Phone (+93) 790721633